After the artificial intelligence revolution,
technology reached its peak,
a historic breakthrough, marking
the end of humans on Earth.
With humanity gone, cities had
never been so clean.
But this extreme cleanliness led to the extinction
of another species, the rats.
[MUSIC]
But one unique and special species
managed to survive and
to subvert its own natural evolution.
The hamsters bravely resisted.
Granted privileged access to the final
remnants of human civilization
scattered across the globe, the hamsters,
guided as if by a divine whisper, rose
from the shadows of captivity.
[MUSIC]
Once mere pets, they shed
their chains and
embarked on remarkable evolution, defying
all expectations with quiet,
unstoppable grace.
They awakened and guided by the memory
of their former masters.
[SOUND] They rose one instinct at a time to conquer
the world that once held them captive.
[MUSIC]
But the spark was also the seed
of their downfall.
They evolved as fast as they multiplied,
built complex societies,
mastered knowledge, dared to reach
beyond their world.
[MUSIC]
But in mirroring their former
human masters,
they inherited more than wisdom.
They walked not into the future, but
into a story already told.
[MUSIC]
What could possibly go wrong?
[APPLAUSE]
They created gods in the full image,
then used them to divide.
Built hierarchies to control
and called them order,
invented paths, borders, and names
for what they feared.
They forged weapons not only to
defend, but to dominate.
They practiced erasure, perfected
hate, engineered extinction.
What once was survival had become...
...ideology
Subtitle